<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Chao Zhang</title>
    <link>http://chaozhang.org/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Chao Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Chao Zhang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chaozhang.org/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://chaozhang.org/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaozhang.org/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an incoming assistant professor at School of Computational Science and Engineering, Georgia Tech from December 2018. I am actively looking for talented and motivated students to work with me. Please email me if you are interested.
I just obtained my Ph.D. at the Computer Science Department of UIUC, advised by Prof. Jiawei Han. My research falls in the area of data mining and machine learning. The overarching goal of my research is to enable machines to turn massive data into actionable insights and intelligent decisions with less supervision and faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://chaozhang.org/home/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaozhang.org/home/news/</guid>
      <description>News  [2018.11]: The code for our CIKM paper on weakly-supervised text classification is released. If you want to use deep neural nets to do text classification but don&amp;rsquo;t have much labeled data, try it out! [2018.11]: Our paper on weakly-supervised hierarchical text classification is accepted by AAAI&amp;rsquo;19. [2018.10]: Our paper on linear-time trajectory similarity computation is accepted by ICDE&amp;rsquo;19. It&amp;rsquo;s up to 100x faster than state-of-the-art trajectory similarity computation techniques and supports all major measures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://chaozhang.org/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaozhang.org/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>