<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GT Big Data Bootcamp</title>
    <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content on GT Big Data Bootcamp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-aws-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-aws-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker in AWS EC2 We developed a Docker image which pre-installed all modules in this bootcamp. You can directly use it in your own environment if you have docker. This page describes how to launch an EC2 instance on AWS and run docker container within it.
Launch an AWS EC2 instance  Open the Amazon EC2 console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/ From the Amazon EC2 console dashboard, click AMIs on left sidebar. Switch Region to N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-azure-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-azure-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker in Azure We could use Azure as a virtual machine provider. If you have no enough resource to host our envornment in local, you can also launch an Azure instance, start a docker service inside, and host our docker image.
We can create a Docker on Ubuntu Server in Azure, and then pull image from hub.docker.com.
Launch an Azure instance Option 1: Launch a Pre-installed Docker Host &amp;ldquo;Docker on Ubuntu Server&amp;rdquo; is a container based on Ubuntu Server 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>Docker Compose ::: tip This is an optional section. Docker Compose is just a utility, which does NOT affect the functionality of the docker image and our course.
You can simply ignore it if you believe the docker commands are enough. :::
Docker Compose is a tool for defining and running multi-container Docker applications. We can write a simple docker-compose.yml file as configure file, and launch a docker container as a service easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-linux/</guid>
      <description>Install Docker In Linux Install Docker on RHEL/CentOS/Fedora  Get Docker CE for CentOS Get Docker CE for Fedora  In brief, after updated your system, you can simply type the follow commands:
sudo yum install docker-ce -y # install docker package sudo service docker start # start docker service chkconfig docker on # start up automatically FAQ  If your SELinux and BTRFS are on working, you may meet an error message as follow:  # systemctl status docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-macos/</guid>
      <description>Install Docker In macOS If you are using macOS, you are supposed to prepare a virtual machine/service to host a real Linux instance, and then control it in the remote.
Currently, there are at least 2 solutions to achieve it.
Option One: Docker.app If you are using macOS, you could follow this guide. Download an image, and drag to your &amp;lsquo;Applications&amp;rsquo; folder, click and run.
 Stable channel Edge channel  Currently, both of them are working pretty fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker-windows/</guid>
      <description>Install Docker In Microsoft Windows ::: tip
If you are interested in software from Microsoft (excluding Microsoft Office products), this link may helps.
You may follow the guide, go to the Imagine login page to download the Windows image for free. :::
Windows Docker Desktop (recommended) An official guide for Windows Docker Desktop could be found here.
Download the image from this link and follow the installer step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://franticnerd.github.io/bigdata-bootcamp/docs/environment/env-local-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker in Local OS ::: tip For the purpose of the environment normalization, we provide a simple docker image for you, which contains most of the software required by this course. We also provide a few scripts to install some optional packages. :::
The whole progress would seem as follow:
 Make sure you have enough resource:  It requires at least 8GB Physical RAM, 16GB or greater would be better It requires at least 15GB hard disk storage   Install a docker environment in local machine Start Docker Service, pull images and create a instance Just rock it!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>