<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Chao Zhang</title>
    <link>http://chaozhang.org/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Chao Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Chao Zhang</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chaozhang.org/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://chaozhang.org/course/19f-cse8803/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaozhang.org/course/19f-cse8803/</guid>
      <description>CSE 8803 DLT: Deep Learning for Text Data Logistics  Lecture time: Monday &amp;amp; Wednesday 3:00PM&amp;ndash;4:15PM Location: CoC Room 52 Instructor: Chao Zhang Teaching Assistant: TBD Piazza: TBD  Piazza will be the main place for course discussions and announcements. If you have questions, please ask it on Piazza first because 1) other students may have the same question; 2) you will get help faster compared to sending emails.  Office Hours:  Instructor Office Hour: TBD TA Office Hour: TBD   Overview This course will introduce state-of-the-art machine learning techniques for mainstay problems in text data analysis, with particular emphasis on deep learning methods that have achieved enormous success recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://chaozhang.org/course/19s-cx4240/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaozhang.org/course/19s-cx4240/</guid>
      <description>CX4240: Introduction to Computational Data Analysis (2019 Spring) Course Information  Lecture time: Mons and Weds, 4:30pm-5:45pm Location: Klaus 1447 Instructors: M. Mahdi Roozbahani and Chao Zhang Teaching Assistant: Hanjun Dai (hanjundai@gatech.edu) and Wendi Ren (wren44@gatech.edu) Piazza: https://piazza.com/class/jqeo3f7s5vc426  Course Overview This course introduces techniques for computational data analysis, with an emphasis on machine learning algorithms and their applications to real-world data. We will investigate the following question: how to extract useful knowledge from data computationally for decision making and task support?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>